# **FAIZAN SAJID**

## Front-end Engineer

## Transforming imagination into reality

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/faizan-sajid

GitHub www.github.com/faizan-sajid

Portfolio portfolio-faizan

Email fsajid68@gmail.com
Contact 9672932853

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Passionate front-end engineer with technical expertise from the School of Accelerated Learning. Dedicated to transforming imagination into reality by creating user-friendly digital experiences. Driven to build awesome websites and apps, I enthusiastically embrace challenges and aim to contribute meaningfully to the evolving world of digital development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### March 2024 - Present

## Frontend developer in Synilogic tech private limited.

- Developed responsive user interfaces using React.js, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Crafting app mockups and prototypes in Figma, collaborating with other designers to create visually engaging and user-friendly web applications & mobile apps.
- Collaborating with teams to refine ideas, focusing on the user experience to make sure the final product is not only functional but also enjoyable to use.

## **June 2021 – Aug 2022**

#### Shift in charge in Svaar process solution pvt ltd.

• Proficiently managed equipment and evaporation process.

## [Dec 2020 - May 2021]

## DET – Diploma engineer trainee in Ansun multitech ltd.

• Operated and maintained electroplating process and equipment, including tank management.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Astrology Kundli - Website.

- Spearheaded the design and smooth implementation of the entire frontend architecture for displaying Kundli and other astrology-related information.
- Integrated API Services to fetch astrological data and Built PDF Generation Functionality.

Technologies: React js, Css, Redux toolkit

## <u>Ai Astrology – Website</u>

• Developed a responsive website frontend that provides AI-powered astrology predictions.

Technologies: Html, CSS, Java script, bootstrap, Aos

Visit at: aiastro

#### **EDUCATION**

**School of accelerated learning:** Product Engineer

Certificate – 2023 Present

Yogiraj institute of technology:

Diploma in chemical engineering Percentage: 74% - Nov 2020

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- React Native
- React.js
- Electron.js
- Redux Toolkit
- Javascript
- Css
- Html

#### SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Team Captain
- Team Player
- Client Care Specialist
- Adaptability and Flexibility
- Researching
- Project Management

#### TOOLS

- Vs Code
- GitHub
- Figma
- Filmora